i want to show you how we can use aws
amplify to build real-time serverless
applications in as little time as
possible
aws amplify is a set of tools and
features that we can use to generate
applications with user authentication
backends with rest and graphql apis
notifications file storage and even ai
all this by writing a very minimal
amount of code before we get started i
would like to invite you to the biggest
i.t conference in korea aws summit korea
is a free online conference that will
have more than 90 talks for developers
of all levels
where you can learn about the newest and
most useful aws products like the one we
are going to be using today this summit
is for developers of any level from
beginners to advanced it will also have
keynotes for business leaders and
decision makers and we will also be able
to listen to keynotes from legends like
the cto of amazon.com
the summit is a hundred percent free so
all you have to do is to click the link
below to register and be able to watch
first we install the aws amplify cli
using mpm then we run the command
amplify configure and that is going to
open the aws website we have to log in
and when we are logged in we press enter
then we choose the region i am going to
choose korea and then we are going to
choose a username for our api key after
we do that we are going to go to a form
to create our api key we're going to
click next next next next and then
create user
there we're going to copy the access key
id
and we are also going to copy paste the
secret access key
after that we will create a profile name
using create react app we are going to
create a new application
then we're going to go inside of the
folder and we're going to run amplify
init
there we are going to say yes to all the
questions
and we're going to choose the aws
profile that we created before
after that we're going to run amplify
add api to create a new api
we are going to select graph
ql
we're going to say continue
we're going to choose the blank schema
and then we will say yes to open our
schema in visual studio code
the schema will be in amplify backend
api
and
schema.graphql in this schema we will
create a new model type called tweet and
we're going to say that the tweet is
going to have id
text and author
after that's done we're going to run
amplify push
we will say yes to everything
and we will tell
amplify to generate
javascript code for the mutations
queries and subscriptions of our api
then we will wait for a couple of
minutes and our api will be ready
then we will run amplify console api to
open our graphql console
and there it is we have a playground for
our api where we can already get started
calling mutations like for example
create tweet these mutations have been
automatically generated for us
we also have queries as well
and here we can see the queries the
mutations and the subscriptions that
have been created for us automatically
by aws amplify
and that's it we now have a graphql api
as you saw we didn't have to write
almost any code everything was generated
for us automatically by aws amplify if
you want to learn more about aws
amplifying all the things it can do on
the aws summit korea there will be a
talk where we will learn how to build
cool things like a serverless call
center using amazon connect and amplify
in addition to the amplify session there
will be other sessions on other i.t
trends and technologies like for example
how korean airlines used blockchain to
digitize logistics how cool is that
to connect amplify with our react
application we are going to install aws
amplify in our project
then we configure amplify by importing
amplify in a generated file that was
created for us with our keys to make the
ui pretty we are going to include pico
css
for the ui of our application we are
going to have two sections one will be a
form where the user is going to write
their name and their tweet and a button
to post it
and on the other section we are going to
have the timeline where the user will
see their tweets
to bring the tweets from our api we are
going to import amplify and we are also
going to import a query called list
tweets this query was generated
automatically for us we also have
mutations generated automatically and we
also have subscriptions generated
automatically as well when we pushed our
api before the tweets are going to live
on the state and i am going to make a
function to fetch the tweets from the
api and put them in the state this
function is going to run only once when
our application loads for the first time
then we are going to render the tweets
using array.map and as you can see the
tweet that we created before it's now in
our ui the form to upload a tweet is
also going to live on the state so we
have to create unchanged event handlers
and we have to connect them to our input
and our text area then we import the
create to it mutation that was generated
for us before and on the unsubmit
function we're going to call that
mutation when the form is submitted
now we should go to the page fill out
the form and when we press post the
mutation should be called so if we
refresh we would see our newest tweet on
top of the list to make everything real
time we are going to import the own
create tweet subscription that was
generated before then we're going to
create a new function where we are going
to subscribe to those updates and when
there is a new tweet coming in we're
going to put it in our state now we can
open our page in two different browsers
and we can see that the messages sent
from firefox appear in the brave browser
and the messages from brave browser
appear in firefox in real time
and we are done we now have a real-time
serverless application that before would
have taken us hours to build and that
instead took us minutes to finish and
this is not all amplify can do if we
want to add authentication to our
application it will take us minutes to
do so amplifier will give us a user
backend using aws cognito and cognito
will handle wrong passwords email
confirmations and even phone login as
well and also if you wanted to save even
more time when making the ui of our
application we could use a set of
pre-made cloud-connected angular view
react and flutter components called
amplify ui let me know in the comments
if you'd like to see more amplified
content maybe we take this app and we
develop it a little bit more we add
authentication we have notifications i
don't know you let me know and don't
forget to register to the aws summit
korea it's a hundred percent free and a
hundred percent online all you have to
do is click the link below to sign up
see you there stay free stay happy stay
healthy come zamida san angelo see you
on the next one bye
[Music]
you